如果你曾有过花费数天去解决一个bug的经历
If you've ever spent days chasing a bug in your code
又或是等你把一个app发布到应用商店时
or released an app to the store only to find out
才发现它有性能上的问题  那么你将会感激
it has performance problems, you will appreciate
接下来这个新的编译与调试功能
the new debugging and testing features
我们已经将它们加入到了最新版本的Android Studio中
we've added in recent versions of Android Studio.
让我们一起来看一下
Let's take a look.
首先  添加memory monitor
Up first, joining the memory monitor
在之前的版本中出现了很久的
that was available on Android Studio for some time
是这个新的CPU monitor
is the new CPU monitor.
这些工具可以让你直观地看到你的app运行状况
These tools give you an overview of how running your app
以及它对硬件设备的影响  因此可以让你很容易察觉到性能问题
is affecting the device so you can spot performance problems early.
你如果想得到更详细的信息
If you need to get more detailed information,
你可以现在就进行Allocation Tracking
you can now start Tracking Object allocations,
或者初始化一段memory dump用作稍后分析
initiate a memory dump for later analysis,
甚至还可以直接从IDE中调用method  进行method tracing
and even start tracing method calls straight from the IDE.
这里还提供了新的performance captures窗格
There's also a new performance captures
用作快速获取任何你所创建对象的内存资源占用信息
pane for quick access to any reports that you've created.
它将变得非常有用  当你试图去发现内存泄露
They can be useful when you're trying to find memory leaks
或者想找到你app的核心部分时
or identify performance critical sections of your app.
但如果知道这些就更好了  比如直接找出内存泄露
But you know what's even better for figuring out where a memory
来自哪里  或者知道与你所创建的对象
leak comes from, knowing which pieces of code
相关的代码是哪些  以防止它们
hold references to your objects, preventing them
被当成垃圾回收
from being garbage collected.
现在这些信息我们可以立刻
You can see that information instantly
通过life debugging session获知
during a life debugging session.
首先  用debug按钮启动你的app
First, start your app using the debug button
或者在代码中间运行
or attach to a writing process.
连接成功后
After a successful connection, the IDE
程序将会停在有断点的地方
will pause execution on any break points that you specify.
你现在可以选择Show referring objects选项
Your can now select the Show referring objects command
从任何当前变量中获知你所需要的信息
on any of the current variables to get the info you need.
再来说说单步调试
And speaking of step-by-step debugging,
你曾经遇到过在第三方库中使用单步调试
have you ever had to use it with some third-party library
最后发现源代码无法读取的情况吗
where the source code was missing from your project?
Android Studio现在内嵌全新的Java反编译器
Android Studio has you covered with a brand new built-in Java decompiler.
从现在起  无论何时你需要读取类内部的源代码
From now on, whenever you need to check
只要它们全部是JAR文件
the internals of a class when all you have is
你只需用鼠标点一下  它们就会出现编辑器中
a JAR file is just one click away in the editor.
并且你甚至可以设置断点
And you can even set break points
从而在已编译的代码中进行单步调试
and do step-by-step debugging inside compiled code.
是不是很酷
How cool is that?
Android Studio 1.2 另一个值得一提的功能
One of the other nifty features that come with Android Studio
就是局部变量的同行显示
1.2 is the inlining of values for local variables
局部变量的值会显示在同一行的右方当debugging时
right there in the Code Editor when debugging.
因此你不必再去variables窗格中找它们了
So you don't have to look for them in the variables pane.
并且  当你的鼠标停在操作符上时
Also, notice that when you mouse over an operator expression,
你当即就可以看到运算结果
you can now see the resulting value in a pop-up
同样  当你鼠标停在变量上时
just like when you mouse over variables
就可以获取到更多详细信息
to inspect them in more detail.
但是你也知道  debugging最难的部分
But you know what the worst thing about debugging
就是debugging本身
is, it's the debugging itself.
这也是为什么你先得反复测试你的apps
That's why you should be testing your apps in the first place.
随着Gradle plug-in和Android Studio的升级
And with recent enhancements in our Gradle plug-in and Android
现在有了新的途径进行编写和自动测试了
Studio, there's now new ways to write and run automated tests.
无论你是从事基于测试的开发
Whether you're doing test-driven development
还是仅仅只想快速地测试你的程序
or just want to test your code quickly,
对设备反复部署测试一直很让人头疼
one of the main pain points was having to deploy test to the device.
并且我们都知道这很花时间
And we all know that takes time.
从Andriod Studio 1.1以后
Starting from Android Studio 1.1,
他们可以支持使用local JVM在你的开发中
there is support for running unit tests on your development
进行单元测试
machine using the local JVM.
要使用这个功能  首先将你的JUnit tests
To use this feature, first put your JUnit tests
放入你的Android module的test文件夹中
in the test folder on your Android module.
Gradle将会创建一个特殊版本的
Gradle will create a special version
Android JAR到类路径中当你运行测试程序时
of Android JAR in the class path when you run the test task.
注意这个JAR实际上不包含任何工作代码
Be aware that this JAR doesn't actually contain working code,
所以你不能使用任何framework类
so you can't use any framework classes.
你应该使用常用的mocking库
You should use one of the popular mocking libraries
比如MOckito  去模拟你所需要的Android依赖项
like MOckito to mock the Android dependencies that you need.
对那些需要运行在设备上的测试程序
For tests that need to run on the device
往往需要完整的framework
where the full framework is required,
这时你可以使用Android test source set
you can use the Android test source set.
这些测试程序就在你app程序的旁边
These tests will be deployed alongside your app
它们可以在指定设备上或者模拟器中运行
and run on the target device or emulator.
然而严格意义上来说  下面的并不属于Android Studio或者Gradle的一部分
While not technically part of Android Studio or Gradle,
但我们最近已经发布了一个库
we have recently released a library
它包含很多可以帮你
that contains many classes that can help you with writing
编写和运行你的测试程序的类
and running your tests.
它就是Andriod Testing Support Library
It's called the Android Testing Support Library.
它可以在Android Support Repository中获取
And it's available through the Android Support Repository.
它提供了最新的  测试framework和API
It gives you the most up-to-date testing frameworks and APIs
它由Google制造  包括一个Android Test Runner with JUnit
made by Google, including an Android Test Runner with JUnit
和Espresso library
for support, the Espresso library
用于功能性UI测试  和UIAutomator等等这些
for functional UI testing, the UIAutomator, and more.
想知道如何用Android Testing Support Library
To find out how to set up your project for running tests
去设置你的工程进行测试
using the Android Testing Support Library,
点击这些链接  查看我们的文档和例程
follow these links and check out our documentation and samples.
如果你有任何问题和建议关于使用Android Studio
If you have any questions or suggestions regarding debugging
去debugging apps  你可以加入我们的讨论
apps using Android Studio, you can join the discussion
在我们的Google+社区
in our Google+ community.
再见咯
See ya.
[MUSIC PLAYING]